こんなめにあわなきゃ
ならねえんだよ…｡
《銀時:なんで…｡
なんで ｵﾚばっか➡
おまけに主食が 柿ﾋﾟｰ｡
ｵﾚ なんか悪いことしたか!?
使えねえと罵られ➡
もう 黙っちゃいられねえ！
(お岩)私を倒したくば➡
もう ひとりとして
いないのだから｡
訳のわからん ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞ旅館で
急に働かされて➡
(お岩)お前は
もう ここで死ぬまで➡
この仕打ち…
もう 我慢ならねえ！
この 仙望郷に
お前の味方など➡
最強のｽﾀﾝﾄﾞを
味方につけるしかあるまいな｡
まぁ それも ﾑﾘな話｡
うおぉぉ…！
疲れてんのに
毎晩 毎晩 ｢UNO｣で眠れねえし！
《ﾌﾞﾘｰﾌ３ ﾃﾒｴら裏切った…!?》
私に こき使われて
生きていくしかないのさ｡
やってやらぁ 閣下もｸｿも
もはや関係ね～！
この温泉旅館
ｵﾚの手で ﾌﾞｯ潰す!!》
《最強のｽﾀﾝﾄﾞ…｡
最強の仲間…｡
Why? Why must this happen to me?
そんなもん…》
Did I do something wrong?
≪(新八)あれ こんなとこで
何やってんすか？
I'm forced to work in some inn for Stands. I'm told I'm useless and I'm tired,
(神楽)起きてるｱﾙか？
(お妙)ｸｯｻ 何ですか このﾆｵｲ!?
but I can't sleep because of them playing UNO every single night.
If that weren't bad enough, I've been living on rice crackers and peanuts!
目の前にあらぁ!!
I can't take it anymore.  I can't stay quiet.
I'm going to do it. "His Excellency" and crap don't matter anymore.
I'm going to crush this hot spring inn!
Brief Trio, you've double-crossed me...
If you want to defeat me, you need the help of the most powerful Stand.
But that's impossible. There isn't anyone in Senbokyo who will help you.
I'm going to have you work here until you die.
The most powerful Stand. The most powerful ally.
Such a person...
Huh? What are you doing here?
Are you awake?
You stink. What is that smell?
They're in front of me!
♪♪～
(ﾚｲ)うっ…！
しばらく
ここで頭を冷やしな ﾚｲ｡
Stay in here for a while to cool down, Rei.
(お岩)まったく 大それたことを
してくれたもんだよ｡
I can't believe what you did. I never thought you'd double-cross me.
まさか ｱﾝﾀが私を裏切るとはねぇ｡
(ﾚｲ)私は…
裏切ったわけじゃない｡
I didn't double-cross you.
(お岩)調子に
乗ってんじゃないよ！
Don't get carried away!
ｱﾝﾀがここで
でかいﾂﾗしてられたのは➡
Who do you think made you stay here?
誰のおかげだと
思ってんだい？
I wasn't working here because I wanted to.
(ﾚｲ)好きで ここで
働いてたわけじゃないよ｡
もとはといえば 女将が…！
お黙り！
Okami, you're the one who started all of this...
Hush!
ｱﾝﾀとは 長いつきあいだから
この程度で済ますけどね➡
We've been together for a long time, so you're getting off easily.
本当だったら魂ごと
粉々に消し去ってるところだよ｡
Otherwise, I would have killed you off and your little soul, too!
You should be thankful I had mercy on you!
少しは 私の優しさに感謝しな！
はぁ… こんなの 間違ってる｡
This is wrong.
(お岩)あん!?
What?
I said, this is wrong. You used to be...
(ﾚｲ)間違ってるって言ったんだよ｡
昔は もっと…！
そのぐらいにしときな！
Cut it out now.
じゃないと
ｱﾝﾀといえど許さないよ｡
If you don't, I won't be able to forgive you.
…女将 ｱﾝﾀも ここも
随分と変わっちまったねぇ｡
Okami, you and this place have changed.
Nothing has changed.
何も 変わりやしないよ｡
(お岩)何も変わらないよう➡
In fact, we purposely tried not to change.
私たちはここまで
ずっとやってきたんだ！
ﾑﾀﾞだよ 私を閉じこめたところで
ｱｲﾂは止められない！
It's useless!
Even if you confine me in here, you can't stop him!
ｷﾞﾝが… ｷﾞﾝがこの宿を
なんとかしてくれる！
Gin... Gin will do something to save this inn!
[Seal]
Sorry to say this, Rei...
(お岩)残念だったね ﾚｲ｡
ｱｲﾂは もう
ｷﾊﾞを抜かれた飼い犬さ｡
...he's become...
...a pet dog without fangs.
["Gin and His Excellency's Good-for-nothings."]
(宴会のざわめき)
[Banquet Hall]
(家康)ﾌﾟﾊｰｯ！
Way to go, Taishogun!
(信長)よっ 征夷大将軍！
天下を飲み干すがごとき➡
It's as if you were drinking in the whole country! We admire you!
みごとな飲みっぷり！
感服しましたぁ！
Hey! Bring more sake! We need more!
(秀吉)お～い 酒をもて～い！
まだまだ 足りぬぞ！
(信長)ささっ 家康様 もう１杯！
Lord Ieyasu, have another shot.
Thank you, but have some yourself, Sir Nobunaga.
(家康)いやいやいや
信長殿も飲んでください！
(家康)あ ﾎﾞｸ つぎますんで！
(信長)いえ ﾎﾞｸがつぎます！
Let me pour some for you.
No, I'll pour more for you.
(家康)ああ いやいや ﾎﾞｸが！
(光秀)料理とお酒 追加！
No, no. Let me do it.
Hey, bring more food and sake!
(幽霊)ああ 忙しい 忙しい！
Boy, we're so busy.
Indeed. We need all the help we can get.
(幽霊)まったく
猫の手も借りたいよ！
[TEL](お登勢)どうだい
ｳﾁの若い衆は？
How're my young people doing?
[TEL]少しは役に立ってるかい？
Have they've been somewhat helpful?
あたしゃ 確かに ｲｷのいいのを
よこしてくれとは言ったがね➡
I did ask you to send a lively guy.
飼い主にまで噛みつくような
狂犬をよこせって➡
But I don't remember asking for a mad dog that bites its owner, Otose.
言った憶えはないよ お登勢｡
(お登勢)ちょいと
ｲｷがよすぎたかい？
Oh, is he a little wilder than you expected?
ｱﾝﾀのところじゃ➡
But I thought you needed a bulldog, not a calm little lap dog.
おとなしいﾏﾙﾁｰｽﾞより
ﾌﾞﾙﾄﾞｯｸﾞのほうが むいてるだろ？
Maybe. But he continually bit me severely.
(お岩)まあね
だが 手ひどく噛まれたよ｡
(お岩)紹介料は 約束の半分だね｡
So, I'll only pay you half of the referral fee.
[TEL](お登勢)話が違うじゃないのさ｡
そいつは ｱﾝﾀの落ち度だろ？
That's not the way I remember it!
That's your fault!
[TEL]こっちだって
人手が足りないところ➡
Although we were shorthanded, I sent them all to you.
人数 貸してやってんだ｡
金は約束どおり払ってもらうよ！
You need to pay as we agreed.
(お岩)不良品つかまされた上
その躾までしてやったんだ｡
You sent me a defective worker, and I disciplined him.
(お岩)こっちが欲しいくらいだよ｡
(お登勢)躾？
I'd say you should pay me instead.
"Disciplined him?"
[TEL](お岩)ああ
少々 痛めつけてやったらね➡
Right! I punished him a bit, and then he became completely obedient.
すっかり
おとなしく従順になったわ｡
(お岩)どうも
ここが気に入ったようでね➡
He seems to like my place.
帰りたくないって言ってるんだが
どうしたもんかね？
And he said he didn't want to go back to you. What should I do?
(お登勢)ちょいと ﾔﾂらを貸すのは
10日間だけと言ったはずだよ｡
Wait. I told you that you could have them for only ten days.
(お岩)本人が帰りたくないと
言ってるんじゃ仕方ないだろ｡
But that's what he wants. I can't do anything about it.
…お岩 さては ｱﾝﾀ➡
Oiwa, have you...
ﾔﾂに惚れたね？
...fallen for him?
(お岩)ｸｯｸｯｸ… お登勢 ｱﾝﾀには
隠しても ﾑﾀﾞみたいだね｡
Otose, I can't hide anything from you, can I?
ｱﾝﾀ あの男 どこで捕まえた？
Where did you find that man?
この短期間で私の信頼していた
幹部を手なずけ➡
He's allied himself with my most trusted worker in a short period.
さらに 下克上を
仕掛けてくるなんぞ➡
And then he plotted to revolt against me. No ordinary man can achieve such a thing.
並の人間の業ではない｡
今は ｸｿの役にも立たない
ただの穀潰しだ｡
Right now he's a useless good-for-nothing.
だが あの男 鍛えれば
とんでもない化け物になるよ｡
But with a bit of training, he'll become a fearsome monster.
この私の後を継ぐのは
ﾔﾂしかいない！
I can't think of anyone better to take over for me.
お登勢…｡
Otose...
(お岩)あのとき
ｱﾝﾀの旦那はもってかれたがね｡
Back then,
you stole away your husband-to-be.
(お岩)今度の男は
ｱﾀｼがいただくよ｡
But this time, I get to take the man.
ﾔﾂは もう私の飼い犬だ｡
He's my dog now.
あの男は 一生 この旅館で
働き続けるのさ… ﾊｯﾊｯﾊ！
That man will have to work the rest of his life in this inn.
[TEL]ﾌｯﾌｯﾌ…｡ そいつは助かるよ｡
That helps me.
(お登勢)女子供を返してもらえば
私は文句はない｡
As long as you send the woman and child back to me, it's fine.
ﾔﾂは 好きにすればいいさ｡
家賃も払わん ろくでなし➡
You can do whatever you want to him.
If I can get rid of that lousy slacker who doesn't pay his rent,
いなくなるなら
こんなに嬉しいことはないよ｡
then there's nothing happier than this.
☎ただし 一つ忠告しとくよ｡
あの男 一筋縄ではいかないよ｡
But let me point out one thing. That man is fierce.
(お岩)ﾌﾝ 躾なら もうしたよ｡
I already disciplined him.
噛みつこうにも 牙なんて
もう生えちゃいないさ｡
Even if he wanted to bite me, he doesn't have fangs anymore.
(お登勢)お岩 牙なんて
何本折ろうが無駄だよ｡
Oiwa, it doesn't matter how many fangs you broke.
躾ができるのは せいぜい獣まで｡
You can discipline a beast, but he's not just a beast. He's worse.
ﾔﾂは 獣なんて
高尚な生き物じゃない｡
(お登勢)ｹﾀﾞﾓﾉだ！
He's a wild animal.
女将 ｷﾞﾝが懲罰房を破って
逃亡しました！
Okami! Gin broke out of the punishment room and escaped!
[TEL]まぁ そういうこった｡
せいぜい気をつけな｡
That's what I told you. You'd better be careful.
(電話が切れる音)
捜せ！
山から下りることはできない｡
Find him!
It would have been impossible for him to go down the mountain!
必ず
この宿のどこかにいるはずだ！
He must be somewhere in this inn!
宿じゅう くまなく捜せ！
Look everywhere!
《いったい どうやって
懲罰房から…｡
Gin, how did he manage to slip out of the punishment room?!
ﾚｲは呪縛房に隔離｡
I trapped Rei in the spell bind cell.
他の連中は憑依状態で
UNOをやり続けているはず｡
And the others are supposed to be possessed by Stands, playing UNO.
ﾔﾂに仲間など１人もいない｡
He couldn't have had any help. So how did he do it?!
なのに どうやって!?》
This is...
《これは まさか…》
Don't tell me...
(笑い声)
Oh, here we go, here, here.
Here we go, here, here!
ﾎﾗ！ ﾎｲ！
《これは… なんでﾔﾂらが!?
This is... Why are they here?!
ｺｲﾂら ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞに憑かれて
UNOをやり続けていたはず｡
They're supposed to be possessed by Stands, playing UNO!
いや あれは ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞ!?
No, they're Stands?!
ﾊﾞ ﾊﾞｶな！ 死んでもいないのに
なぜｽﾀﾝﾄﾞに!?》
It can't be! How could they be Stands when they're not even dead?!
《まさか ﾔﾂらがｷﾞﾝを…》
Can it be, that they helped Gin?!
(TAGOSAKU)生霊だ｡
ん？
They're living ghosts.
(TAGOSAKU)ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞにとり憑かれる
ということは➡
Being possessed by a Stand means to have a foreign spirit enter your body.
つまり 異質な霊が
身体に侵入してくるということ｡
そのため 身体に元あった
ﾔﾂら自身のｽﾀﾝﾄﾞが➡
And because of it,
their original Stands rejected themselves from the body, escaping as living ghosts.
拒否反応を起こして
生きながら外に出たんだ｡
(お岩)いや ここが日本有数の
霊場だとしても➡
No.
Even if this place is one of the foremost spiritual sites in Japan,
それだけの理由で
ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞの状態になるとは考えにくい｡
that can't be the only reason for them to become Stands.
あっ！ まさかｱｲﾂら➡
Don't tell me,
ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞになってまで
仲間を救おうとしているのかい!?
they went out of their way to become Stands because they wanted to help him?!
そんなﾊﾞｶな！
It can't be!
Oh, how fun this is!
あぁ 愉快 愉快！
こんなに楽しい宴会は
生まれて初めてだ｡
This is the most fun party I've ever been to since I was born.
何 言ってんですか｡
あ？
What are you talking about?
It's not since you were born. Don't you mean since you've died?
生まれて初めてじゃなくて
死んで初めての間違いでしょ｡
ﾊﾊﾊｯ！ いっけね そうだった｡
Shoot, you're right!
What?!
《なっ！ 家康公が消滅した!!
Lord Ieyasu has disappeared!
客が次々に消滅していく！
And the other guests are disappearing!
あの男 まさか気づいたのか？
ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞの倒し方に｡
It can't be! That man found out how to defeat the Stands?!
そう ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞを倒すという行為は➡
That's right.
You don't defeat Stands by holding them down by physical force,
腕力でもって
敵をねじ伏せることでも➡
頭を使って
罠に はめることでもない｡
or to trick them by using your head.
すなわち… 成仏｡
Defeating Stands means
sending them to heaven.
この世に未練を残し
さまようｽﾀﾝﾄﾞたち｡
The Stands wander this world because of their regrets.
ﾔﾂらは充足感や幸福感を得て
初めて あの世にいける｡
Only when they feel satisfied and happy can they go into heaven.
そう ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞを倒すには
腕力も知力もいらない｡
Yes. You don't need muscle and intelligence to defeat Stands.
必要なのは…➡
All you need is...
思いやり 気づかい 優しさ｡
[Sympathy]
[Consideration]
[Kindness]
sympathy, consideration or kindness.
そんな 学級目標のようなものが
強力な武器になるのだ》
The kind of things you learn in class become the ultimate weapons!
[Ask not until we have won the war.]
Everyone!
みんな！ あの世にいってもｵﾚ
みんなのこと忘れないから！
I won't forget any of you after you enter the afterlife!
どうか 安らかに眠ってください！
May you rest in peace!
じゃあ １曲 歌います！
I'm going to sing a song.
『千の風になって』｡
"A Thousand Winds"
♪♪～
[A Thousand Winds]
[Performed by Gintoki Sakata]
Do not stand at my grave
[Do not stand at my grave]
and weep,
[and weep,]
I am not
[I am not there,]
not sleep
[I do not sleep.]
(お岩)あぁ～!!
客が 大量に成仏していく｡
[I am a thousand winds]
Ahh! My guests are going to heaven!
I am a thousand winds
止めろ！ 誰か ﾔﾂらを止めろ！
Stop them! Somebody! Stop them!
[I am a thousand winds that blow.]
Brief Trio, go stop them! Or else all of our guests will disappear!
ﾌﾞﾘｰﾌ３ 追え！
このままじゃ 宿の客は全滅だ｡
待ってください 光秀殿が
半分 成仏しかかってるっす｡
Please wait! Sir Mitsuhide has already made a stairway to heaven!
that blow,
(お岩)何してんだよ ﾃﾒｴはよ！
What the hell are you doing?!
(信長)しっかりしろ 光秀！
(光秀)やめて やめて！
Come on, Mitsuhide!
Stop! Stop feeding me those heartwarming words.
(光秀)優しい言葉かけないで
ﾏｼﾞいくから ﾏｼﾞいくから｡
Or I'm gonna come... I'm gonna come...
(お岩)いいから
早くいけっつってんだよ！
Just go now!
I am a thousand winds
♪♪｢千の風になって｣
(信長)ｸｿｯ どこ行った？ ﾔﾂら｡
(光秀)四方八方から➡
Damn it! Where did they go?
I hear "A Thousand Winds" from all sides.
『千の風になって』が
聞こえてくるぞ｡
(光秀)あぁ もう ｵﾚ ﾀﾞﾒかも｡
I don't think I can hold it anymore.
(秀吉)光秀殿 ｵﾚに
殺されたときのことを思い出せ｡
Sir Mitsuhide, think of when I killed you!
憎いだろ ｵﾚが憎いだろ！
You hate me don't you? You hate me!
Sorry, but I have something to tell you before I go.
すまん 消える前に ひと言
言っておきたいことがある｡
聞いてくれるか？
Will you listen to me?
殿 本能寺 すみませんした｡
My lord, I'm sorry about Hononji Temple.
あぁ～!! やめて やべぇよ！
Stop! Shoot!
消える前に ひと言とかやめて｡
Stop saying, "I have something to say before I go!"
あっ やばい ｵﾚ やばい
ｵﾚ 泣きそう｡
Oh shit, oh shit! I'm close to tears. You're doing this on purpose, aren't you?!
お前 今のわざとだろ！
殿 しっかりしてください！
My lord! Hold on!
(信長)うっ うぅ… 秀吉｡
Hideyoshi!
(信長)消える前に ひと言
言っておきたいことがある｡
I have one thing to say before I go.
Stop! Stop! I don't want to hear it! I don't!
(秀吉)やめて… やめて！
聞きたくない 聞きたくない！
『ｱﾙﾏｹﾞﾄﾞﾝ』 ﾂﾀﾔに返しといて｡
Please return "Armageddon" to the Tsutaya video rental store for me.
(秀吉)謝れ！
猿って言ったの謝れ！
Apologize! Say you're sorry for calling me a monkey!
ﾌｯ｡
光秀殿！
Sir Mitsuhide!
光秀殿 『ｱﾙﾏｹﾞﾄﾞﾝ』で
成仏しちゃったよ どういうこと？
Sir Mitsuhide went to heaven from hearing "Armageddon"! What's going on?!
(神楽)おい｡
えっ？
Hey!
Oh, I'm sorry. I've confused you with Jean-Claude Van Damme.
あっ すみません
ｼﾞｬﾝｸﾛｰﾄﾞ･ｳﾞｧﾝﾀﾞﾑと間違えました｡
Ahh!
あぁ～!!
Jean-Claude Van Damme! He's so cool!
(秀吉)ｼﾞｬﾝｸﾛｰﾄﾞ･ｳﾞｧﾝﾀﾞﾑ！
超かっこいいじゃん｡
(信長)落ち着け！ 猿
お前 全然似てないから｡
Calm down, monkey! You don't look like him at all!
東洋人 丸出しだから｡
(神楽)いや そっちじゃなくて➡
You're completely Asian!
No, not you. I was referring to you, Mr. Nobunaga.
信長さん あなたです｡
Ahh! He's awesome! Jean-Claude!
(信長)あぁ～!!
超かっこいいじゃん ｼﾞｬﾝｸﾛｰﾄﾞ｡
(秀吉)殿！ 落ち着いてください
ｼﾞｬﾝｸﾛｰﾄﾞ ｵﾚだから｡
My lord! Please calm down. I'm Jean-Claude!
神楽ちゃん もういいよ 行こう｡
とどめ刺さなくていいｱﾙか？
Kagura, that's enough. Let's go.
Should I finish it?
Oh?
あれ？ ｷﾐ 一見 地味だけど➡
You looked like a really simple guy at first glance,
ﾒｶﾞﾈ取ったら
かっこよさげじゃない？
but you're much better looking without glasses.
Arghhh!
あぁ～!!
Shin!
(お妙)新ちゃん！
やられた！ やられたけど➡
They got me! They got me, but I feel kinda happy!
ちょっと嬉しい！
(信長)やったぞ！
I did it!
(秀吉)やったっすね！
さすが 殿｡
Good job, my lord!
Ahhh! Don't say good job!
あぁ～!! さすがとか言うなや｡
M-M-My lord!
と と と と… 殿!!
いや ちょっと待って！
もういいでしょ これ｡
No! Hold on! That's enough! It's over! Hey!
もう 勝負ついたでしょ これ｡
(お妙)行くわよ｡
Let's go.
(秀吉)あれ？ ｷﾐ 芸能人に
似てるとか よく言われない？
Oh? Did anyone ever tell you that you looked like a celebrity?
あの… あれ！
誰だっけ？ 伊藤…｡
Um, who was it? Mi Ito...
Wow, sis, his words didn't move you a bit!
うわぁ さすが 姉上
全然 動じませんね｡
だって
当たり前のことじゃないの｡
Why should they? It's the truth.
I am a thousand...
♪♪｢千の風…｣
ﾑﾀﾞだよ｡
It's useless.
私の旦那にゃ
そんなもの効かない｡
It won't work on my husband.
Is that so?
やっぱり？ っつうか
実は ｻﾋﾞ以外 うろ覚えなんだよね｡
Actually to tell you the truth, except for the main bars, I only vaguely know this song.
やってくれたじゃないのさ｡
You sure have done it.
さすがは
私の見込んだ男だけあるわ｡
Just what I'd expect from the man I've set my sight on.
ただ ちぃと おｲﾀが過ぎたね｡
But you did a bit too much.
Heh. What's wrong with sending dead people to heaven?
ﾌﾝ！ 亡者を成仏させて何が悪い？
Dead people go to the afterlife. It's their natural providence.
死んだﾔﾂは あの世にいくのが
自然の摂理ってもんさ｡
それを こんな所に いつまでも
ﾈﾁﾈﾁ 縛りつけて➡
Yet you keep them here for no reason.
What do you want to do with them, anyway, old hag?
ﾊﾞｱさん… ｱﾝﾀ
いったい 何がしてぇんだ？
もう やめにしようぜ｡
I don't know what the deal is here, but let's stop licking on each other's wounds.
未練だか なんだか知らねえが
こんな所で傷のなめ合いすんのは｡
I'll send all of you to the afterlife.
ｵﾚが まとめて
あの世送りにしてやらぁ｡
ﾌｯ… あの世に行くのは
どちらかね？
Let's just see who will be sent to the afterlife.
(お岩)ｱﾊﾊﾊﾊﾊ！
Gin, I'll show you what a real Stand user is...
ｷﾞﾝ！ 本物のｽﾀﾝﾄﾞ使いってﾔﾂが
何か➡
...in the worst way possible!
身をもって 知るがいいわ！
The most powerful Stand, Tagosaku, has finally shown up!
《出やがったな！
最強のｽﾀﾝﾄﾞ TAGOSAKU!!
戦う前から わかる…｡
この空気を伝わる 邪悪な気！
I can feel it even before the battle! This evil aura I feel...
He's totally different from the other Stands!
ｺｲﾂは 今までの他のｽﾀﾝﾄﾞとは
まったく別もの！
I mean, I see something like "Gogogogo"!
だって ほら なんか
｢ｺﾞｺﾞｺﾞｺﾞ｣って 見えるもん！
あれ あの漫画で見た
｢ｺﾞｺﾞｺﾞｺﾞｺﾞ｣だよね？ あれ！》
That's the same "Gogogogo" I see in that manga, right?
Yes...
(お岩)そうさ… ｳﾁの旦那は➡
My husband is not just any Stand.
そんじょそこらの
ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞなんかじゃない｡
You can't just sing and send him to heaven like everyone else.
お前の付け焼き刃の歌なんかで
成仏するような➡
He's completely different from other Stands.
なまやさしい低級ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞとは
まったく別ものさ｡
Because he has an obsession with this world? Or a grudge?
この世への執着？ いや 怨念か？
違うね｡ これは 絆さ｡
No, it's because of the bond between two people.
そう 例えて言うならば
被告に付き添う 弁護士｡
For example, a lawyer and defendant, a coach and player,
選手に付き添う ｺｰﾁ
ｶﾞﾝﾀﾞﾑに付き添う ｶﾞﾝｷｬﾉﾝ｡
or Guncannon and Gundam, or Tonkatsu and cabbage, or Mana and Kana!
ﾄﾝｶﾂに付き添う ｷｬﾍﾞﾂ
ﾏﾅに付き添う ｶﾅ｡
Hey! The last couple of examples fall short, don't they?!
おい！ 最後のほう
もう なんか適当すぎねえ!?
Humph. It means our bond is something that cannot be severed so easily.
ﾌﾝ… 切っても切れない
間柄ってことさ｡
いい歳 こいて ﾉﾛｹた～ね｡
聞いてあきれるぜ ｸｿばばあ！
Keep that kind of sappy talk to yourself, you old hag!
What? Don't you have a sweetheart? How pathetic!
なんだい？ ﾉﾛｹる相手も
いないのかい？ 情けない男だね｡
大きなお世話だ ﾊﾞｶﾔﾛｳ！
ｵﾚだってな…｡
Oh, leave me alone, you bitch!
I...
(お岩)いねえんだったら
引っ張るんじゃねえ！
Don't take your time if you don't have any!
うるせぇ！
少しは 見栄 張らせろよ!!
Shut up! Don't make me miserable!
あと 引くだろ こういうの！
傷つくんだよ!!
I tend to drag stuff like this out! It really hurts me, you know!
ﾌﾝ！ まぁ いい｡
どうせ すぐ終わるよ｡
Anyway, it'll be over soon.
いつだって どんなことからも
TAGOSAKUは 私を護ってくれる｡
No matter when or what it is, Tagosaku will protect me.
Ever since that time...
あのときから…｡
Yes...
(お岩)そう… ずっと
私を護り続けてくれる｡
He has always protected me.
♪♪～
(お岩)ずっと…｡
Always...
《あれは
自ら ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞを取り込んで！》
Is she taking the Stand into her own body?
(お岩)勘違いしちゃいけないよ｡
You have it all wrong.
A Stand user is not just about controlling the Stands as you command.
ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞ使いとは ただｽﾀﾝﾄﾞを
手足のように使うだけじゃない｡
ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞを己が身に憑依させ➡
Being able to take in the Stand within your own body,
yet still retaining your own consciousness,
意識を支配されることなく➡
and controlling that immense power.
その強大な力を操る｡
それが 真のｽﾀﾝﾄﾞ使い｡
That's a true Stand user.
ｷﾞﾝ… ｷｻﾏにﾏﾈできるか？
Gin, can you possibly do this?
《ばばあの体が
別人のように変化していく…｡
The old lady's body is transforming into someone else.
This is...a true Stand user?!
これが これが本物のｽﾀﾝﾄﾞ使い…｡
But you're just His Excellency!
…って ただの閣下だろうが～!!》
ﾌﾞﾜｰｯﾊﾊﾊﾊ！
お前も蝋人形にしてやろうか？
I'll turn you into a wax dummy, too!
あっ!?
D-Don't underestimate me, you old hag!
なっ… ﾅﾒんな この ｸｿばばあ！
うっ！
うっ!?
うわっ！
ぐはっ！
うおっ！
♪♪～
うっ… あぁ…｡
えいっ！
ぐはっ！ うっ!?
あっ！
♪♪～
うっ… うぅ…｡
なんだい こんなもんかい｡
Is that it? We're just getting started here.
これからが本番だってのに｡
Don't tell me you're down already.
まさか もう のびちまったって
わけじゃないよね？
おりゃ！
ぐはっ！
ﾌﾊﾊﾊ… やっぱり まだ動ける力が
残っていたようだね｡
Just as I thought, you still have the energy left to move around.
それじゃあ これで とどめだよ｡
So,
this will be the final blow!
ｵﾗｵﾗ ｵﾗｵﾗ ｵﾗｵﾗ ｵﾗｵﾗ！
Even this isn't enough to atone your sins for wrecking my inn!
この お岩の宿をﾒﾁｬﾒﾁｬにした罪は
こんなもんじゃ消えないよ！
An ignorant brat like you talking like you know it all!
何も知らないｶﾞｷが
知ったふうな口をききやがって！
It's providence that a dead person goes to the next world. Yes, that's right!
｢死んだﾔﾂは
あの世にいくのが自然の摂理｣➡
ああ そうさ！ そのとおりさ！
だが 落ちる水が➡
But not everyone can go to heaven.
すべて盆に
おさまるとは限らない！
Some people can't go there!
どうしても こぼれ落ちちまう
ﾔﾂらだって いるんだ！
どうしたって
未練を断ち切れないﾔﾂがいる｡
There're people who can't stop thinking about this world.
Or there're people who have deep scars that have yet to heal.
どうしたって
癒えない傷を持つﾔﾂがいる！
This is the only place for people like them!
ここは そんな行き場のない
亡者たちの唯一の居場所なんだ！
ｱﾝﾀに… ｱﾝﾀに
それを奪う権利なんか➡
You...
You have no right to take it from them!
ありゃしないんだよ！
だったら… ｱﾝﾀに➡
If that's true,
you don't have the right to keep them here, either, do you?
ﾔﾂらをここに縛りつける権利も
ありゃあしねえんじゃないのか？
盆から こぼれ落ちてるのは
ﾔﾂらなんかじゃねえ｡
What keeps them here is not their failure to go to heaven.
女将… ﾃﾒｴだ！
Okami, it's because of you!
《ﾊﾞ… ﾊﾞｶな!?
N-No way.
It can't be!
まさか これは… これは…！》
This is...
うっ！
ﾊﾊﾊﾊﾊｯ！
You old, dirty hag!
この薄汚い くさればばあが！
[Tou (Sugar)]
I'll make sugar candy out of you!
お前も糖人形にしてやろうか～！
[To be continued]
[His Excellency VS His Excellency]
[Final Round!!]
Buwahahaha!! The next episode:
"Be Careful When Using Ghost Stories"
[On the morning of our Shinto purification, an unanticipated situation has occurred.]
[If we knew this was going to happen, we should've gone sooner...]
[See you again next time!]